Adam Hawkin

Email: adamhawkin@hotmail.co.uk

in: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adamhawkin

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently working in Leeds as a Developer for one of the largest telecommunication companies in the UK. I am an honest and conscientious worker with a strong attention to detail. My degree and past work experience have given me opportunities to prove I can stay self-motivated, work under pressure, develop my communication and technical abilities. Lastly, I thoroughly enjoy working on projects both in my job and in my own time to further my software development skills.

EDUCATION

2005 – **2010**: **Kettlethorpe High School** – Achieving 10 GSCEs, ranging from A-C including Maths, English and Science.

2010 – **2013**: **Outwood Grange Academy Sixth Form** – Achieving an A* in A2 Product Design, an A in A2 ICT and a C in AS Physics.

2013 – 2016: Leeds Beckett University – BSc (Hons) Computing – Graduated with First-class honours

Modules of interest:

- Adv. Internet Development I was very interested in this module as it introduced me to a range of new technologies and deepened my knowledge of web development. It covered OO (Object Oriented) development techniques using PHP, MVC frameworks, XML and JSON, Rest APIs, Ajax and AngularJS.
- Adv. Software Engineering Part A of this module covered the conversion of a Java program to a C# windows form application. Part B required me to create a bug tracking system using windows forms and a locally stored relational database; I also had to test my classes using unit tests.
- Production Project For my final year project I am developing a website that aggregates rugby league news using RSS data feeds. The news articles are clustered together using named entities which are identified by a using combination of string matching techniques such as levenshtein distance. Some of the technologies I am using include: ASP.NET MVC, Entity framework, NPM, Gulp.JS, Less, AJAX and MS SQL Server.

EMPLOYMENT AND WORK EXPERIENCE

2011: PureNet – 4 Weeks Work Experience

I shadowed a member of the web development team, learning how a team operates together to produce a finished product. I also got the chance to work on a live project, styling part of the mobile for In-time (http://www.intime.co.uk/) using CSS in Visual Studio.

2013: Freelancing – Time Bakery

I produced a website for a small café/bakery business in my local city. I used a variety of skills such as PHP, CSS and the Bootstrap 3 framework to build the website. This project strengthened my communication skills as well as my problem solving abilities.

28th July – 22nd August 2014: Branded3 – 4 Weeks Work Experience

During the 4 week period I worked as a member of the development team, mainly working on front end website projects. I got the chance to learn some new front end development technologies and skills such as LESS and SASS, as well as being introduced to asp.net MVC and produced a small C# ASP.Net test project.

7th October 2014 – June 2016: Branded3 – Junior Web Developer (Part-time)

During my time at University I worked 12.5 hours a week as a junior developer at Branded3. My first role involved helping the frontend development team write HTML and style PHP and ASP.net website projects using LESS and SASS with the Bootstrap framework. In 2016, I moved into a more backend development focused role, working on C# ASP.Net MVC websites that use the Sitecore CMS platform. These projects exposed me to a variety of technologies/platforms such as MongoDB, package managers (NPM and Bower), Gulp.Js and New Relic.

Whilst at Branded3 I gained a deeper understanding of agile project development and team work flow, using source control technologies such as SourceTree, GitHub and BitBucket. Furthermore, I had to stick to strict deadlines and be conscious of client budgets using tools such as Jira, MantisBT and 10000ft to aid this.

July 2016 – December 2017: Sky UK – Associate Software Developer

January 2018 - Present: Sky UK - Developer

HOBBIES

My hobbies include video games, programming, watching rugby league and supporting Castleford Tigers on a weekly basis. I also play squash most weekends, like going to the cinema and listening to music.